<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on JamesShaw.info</title>
    <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on JamesShaw.info</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jjshaws.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on A People&#39;s History of the United States by Howard Zinn</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/aphotus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/aphotus/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished Howard Zinn&amp;rsquo;s A People&amp;rsquo;s History of the United States (2003 edition), as I wanted to learn more about the effectiveness of grassroots activism. I originally found this book on a list of Noam Chomsky’s suggested readings. The author, Howard Zinn, was a Political Science professor at Boston University. It turns out that Chomsky and Zinn had a close relationship, first meeting back in the &amp;rsquo;60s in Boston, where they became friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quinault Rain Forest</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/quinault/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/quinault/</guid>
      <description>The mystic Quinault Rain Forest. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Big Caterpillar</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/abigcaterpillar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/abigcaterpillar/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the biggest caterpillar I&amp;rsquo;ve seen anyway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overgrown</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/fence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/fence/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fireworks</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/fireworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/fireworks/</guid>
      <description>Fireworks over the water</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raw Photos</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/raw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/raw/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it&amp;rsquo;s time to post some raw photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candle</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/candle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/candle/</guid>
      <description>A candle, it&amp;rsquo;s almost done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Park</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/vp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/vp/</guid>
      <description>These pictures were taken in and around Volunteer Park, in Seattle Washington. This park opened in 1901 and was designed by the Olmstead brothers, who believed that the park would be a serene place for nearby residents to enjoy. The surrounding neighbourhood used to be called &amp;ldquo;Millionaire&amp;rsquo;s Row&amp;rdquo; due to the opulent mansions and estates nearby. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purple-striped Jelly</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/monterey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/monterey/</guid>
      <description>The Purple-striped Jelly has a painful, but not deadly sting. Its limited range is off the coast of California. This specimen was photographed in the Monterey Bay Aquarium. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hail on Cougar Mountain</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/hail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/hail/</guid>
      <description>After an unseasonably warm day, a hailstorm hit at the Cougar Mountain lookout. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver Snow</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/vancouversnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/vancouversnow/</guid>
      <description>The December 20 2022 snowfall delayed Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s buses and led to the cancellation of UBC&amp;rsquo;s exams for the day. My final Computer Science exam was impacted, rescheduled for some other time in the new year. So, what better way to spend the afternoon than to walk along Jericho beach? A thick layer of snow is a rarity in Vancouver. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late Fall in Vancouver</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/latefall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/latefall/</guid>
      <description>In the late Fall, the air is sharp. The colour in Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s foliage holds on for another month, some of the greens even make it to the Spring. When there&amp;rsquo;s light outside, it&amp;rsquo;s nearly a constant sunrise or sunset, drawing long shadows here and there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old Dhaka Street Food Vendors</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/streetfood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/streetfood/</guid>
      <description>The Old Dhaka District of is known for its late night street food. Some local favorites include lamb skewers, claypot chai (Motka) and flaming paan leaves (fire paan). Street food vendors have the tough job of getting attention while competing with honking cars, rickshaws and other salespeople. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balinese Macaques</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/macaques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/macaques/</guid>
      <description>These pictures are Balinese long-tailed macaques in a monkey sanctuary in Ubud, Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surma River Workers</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/surmariverlabourers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/surmariverlabourers/</guid>
      <description>On a trip to Sylhet in Bangladesh, I spent an afternoon touring the Surma river in a Sampan-style boat. Along the river, there were teams of labourers using buckets and shovels to transfer sand from the riverbed into boats, then down the riverbank into piles. According to our driver, these labourers are paid about 80 Taka (~1 CAD) per cubic foot of sand delivered to the riverbank. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Galata Bridge Fishermen</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/istanbulfishermen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/istanbulfishermen/</guid>
      <description>The Galata bridge in Istanbul is a popular fishing spot for locals. It links the oldest part of Istanbul, hosting the Ottoman imperial palace and religious landmarks to the newer, more secular part of the city. Here, fishermen of stand close to one another, landing palamut (Atlantic bonito) and cinekop (bluefish).
The first photo looks South, facing Eminönü district, with Nuruosmaniye Mosque visible across the river.
Istanbul happens to lie European-Asian continental border.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Water</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/winterwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/winterwater/</guid>
      <description>Taken during the Winter of 2018 these pictures give a sense of Winter near the Great Lakes in Ontario. Plants and wildlife are quiet while water flows, falls and freezes. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misc By Year</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/photos/misc/</guid>
      <description>A loose series of images from 2019 to 2022</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing Support Optimization</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/manufacturing-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/manufacturing-optimization/</guid>
      <description>I worked with NewPro3D, a Vancouver based 3D printing company to help them better understand the importance of support structure placement in their printing process. Starting from first principles, my team developed models for failure as a function of printing parameters such as print speed, layer thickness. Our model allowed the company to determine the optimal distance between support structures, ultimately decreasing the print time, print cost and time spent removing supports after curing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bone Scaffold Strength Testing</title>
      <link>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/bone-scaffolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jjshaws.github.io/posts/bone-scaffolds/</guid>
      <description>Bone disorder prevalence is increasing, largely due to an aging global population. Consequently, researchers are looking to novel methods for the treatment and replacement of atrophied bone. In this project, I tested the mechanical strength of a variety of 3D printed bone scaffold structures. They were designed such that so called &amp;ldquo;bone resorption&amp;rdquo;, or a prosthetic&amp;rsquo;s ability to be reintegrated into the body would occur. I compared comventional bone scaffold designs (truss and TPMS) with topologically optimized designs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
